Derrik Dennis

derrik@austin.rr.com | 512-826-5175 | Elgin, Texas 78621 |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/derrikdennis

Portfolio: https://bit.ly/derrikdennis

An enthusiastic aficionado of data currently in the late stages of a career comeback as an associate data scientist. Seven years prior experience in consultative roles working primarily with marketing teams at major telecom players. Additional work experience includes being a member of project management leadership including initiation, planning, project execution, and enacting statistics and analytics to monitor lifecycle. Possesses an analytical mindset with the ability to adapt to multiple projects at once. Endowed with strong communication skills able to understand complex analytical modeling and convey their meaning easily. Recent graduate of the UT - Austin Data Analysis and Visualization boot camp, a rookery for those pursuing a role as an associate data scientist.

Skills

- Python
- Tableau
- JavaScript
- SQL
- Data Visualizations
- SAS

- HTML5
- CSS
- User Interface Designs
- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Natural Language Processing
- Data Modeling
 - Statistics

Recent Projects

Project Spotify | github.com/saharalaei/Final-Project | https://bit.ly/DAbootcampSA

- Developed an app to look into a user's top artists and music choices, selecting potential new tracks using machine learning, and provide comparisons of the top artists and tracks in the last year
- Scraped data at spotifytracks.com, conducted data manipulations and transformations, developed Tableau reporting tool, embedded Spotify player into Tableau tool, created dashboard framework for project, developed team page using CSS transform properties
- Tools / Programming languages Used: Python Flask, d3.js, Tableau, Machine Learning, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4.

The Story of Citibike | github.com/derrikdennis/ProjectEnergy | https://tabsoft.co/DDCitibike

- Impact analysis of the first wave of Covid-19 in New York City as it relates to CitiBike
- Reviewed ridership and membership trends covering August 2018, August 2019 and August 2020 data
- Tools / Programming languages Used: Tableau

Relevant Experience

Director, Sales and Business Development Arbitron Mobile, Oakland, CA May 2012 - November 2013

- Acquired \$2.5 Million flagship contract with Facebook using advanced analytics using data from Arbitron Mobile's mobile app
- Won \$500K in contracts Developed 3 new front-end standardized reports in collaboration with Arbitron Mobile's operations team for the verticals of carriers, mobile app software and cellular hardware.
- Key figure in managing external clients and partners with understanding of business domain, frequent communication, expectation management, and meeting deadlines.

Director, Telecom Practice

January 2008 – May 2012

Nielsen, San Francisco, CA and Johannesburg, South Africa

- 2010 Nielsen Global Telecom Practice Employee of the Year
- Drove initiative for further implementation for Mobile Insights through the design and creation of enhanced back-end changes in a role similar to a data engineer which brought in an additional \$1.5 million.
- Won \$880K contract with Nokia in the Middle East / African market by utilizing internal products to craft sophisticated analysis.
- Piloted comprehensive presentations to drive customer success for Verizon Wireless performing analytical modeling including marketing mix modeling and attribution across multiple complicated datasets.

Additional Experience

Dining Room Manager Siena Ristorante, Austin, TX March 2018 - Present

- Implemented standardization methods enhancing the customer experience by actively and consistently supporting efforts in reducing errors
- Rolled out of new reservation protocols bringing in record revenue for Q1 and Q2 2019.
- Created the standardization for banquets which enabled a 10-15% reduction of errors and faster turn-time for each course.

Education

Certificate, Data Analysis and Data Visualization, University of Texas, Austin, TX

October 2020

Bachelor's Degree, Communications, The Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL

Bachelor's Degree, Meteorology, The Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL